Andy Montalvo Fernández

Address: Retorno Fuerzas Zapatistas 140, Colonia Bosques de la Alameda, Celaya.

Guanajuato, Mexico. ZIP Code: 38033 **Phone:** +52 461 253 4450

Phone: +52 461 253 4450 Email: amontalvof92@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Telecommunication and Electronics Engineer specialized in software and web development, and database administration. With experience in front-end programming using HTML5, JavaScript and CSS, back-end programming using Codelgniter (PHP) and Flask (Python), deep learning using PyTorch (Python) and computer vision using OpenCV (Python).

SKILLS

Languages: Spanish (Native speaker) and English (TOEFL B2) **Programming:** HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, PHP, SQL, Python

Frameworks and libraries: JQuery, Bootstrap, Codelgniter, Flask, OpenCV, PyTorch,

NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite

Other tools: Pentaho Data Integration

Working with Nvidia Jetson Nano and Raspberry Pi

Microsoft Office package: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint

Other skills: Teamwork, self-motivated, understanding of user experience, accurate,

initiative, organized.

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2017 - 12/2018

Web Developer and Database Administrator ETECSA- Empresa de Telecomunicaciones de Cuba S.A. Havana, Cuba Responsibilities:

- Wrote codes for websites using a variety of languages (Data base: Microsoft SQL Server and PostgreSQL. Languages: ASP, Python and PHP). Conducted quality assurance tests to look for errors, developing and implementing effective solutions to the issues.
- Designed applications that helped to increase company efficiency and productivity by 80%.
- Worked on back-end development tasks such as coding, ensuring work was done with precision.
- Implemented and maintained security measures to prevent unauthorized disclosure or accidental damage.
- Oversaw database system development to ensure requirements were met and modifications were made when necessary.
- Performed regular maintenance, troubleshooting, system restores, and system backups when necessary.

09/2016 - 06/2017

Front-end Programmer Ministerio del Transporte. Havana, Cuba

Responsibilities:

- Specialized in HTMLS, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Collaborated with designers and other team members to create clean interfaces and to optimize the experience and interactions of the user.
- Completed front-end development tasks and ensured user experience design was incorporated into websites for optimal user accessibility.
- Maintained high productivity and efficiency.
- Met with management and clients to determine the needs of a website to ensure it reached its goals.
- Remained up to date on current development practices and standards to produce only the latest and highest-quality work.
- Worked with team members, communicating about the information to be contained on the website and how to effectively present it.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2021

Master of Science in Electronics Engineering, Technological Institute of Celaya. Celaya, Mexico. Fields of study: Electronics, Deep Learning and Computer Vision using Python.

2011 - 2016

Telecommunication and Electronics Engineer, José Antonio Echeverría Technological University of Havana-Cujae. Havana, Cuba. Thesis: "Vibration measurement for leak detection in water distribution networks". Focus on digital signal processing using Python.